Morning!
早啊
So coincidental!
这么巧啊
Is it?
巧吗
Isn't this the only route
去吃早餐
for breakfast?
这不是必经之路吗
Mr. Zhao.
赵经理
What's with
你这今天穿的
your outfit?
是什么
You look like a host.
跟个司仪似的
You're not waiting for me, are you?
你不会是在等我吧
Do you really want me to wait for you?
你就这么希望我等你
I, um,
我这
I have some dates lined up
我这回去有
after I get back.
其他约会
But,
不过
if you need companion,
你需要人陪
considering
看在
the years we've been colleagues,
这么多年同事的情分上
I'll keep you company.
我就陪陪你
Wearing a suit,
穿西装
and a tie.
打领带
Are you helping grandma collect clams?
去海边陪奶奶捡花蛤
Can't you say something nice?
你就不能说点好的吗
Mr. Ji.
纪总
Boss.
领导
Surprised, aren't you?
是不是有点惊喜
I'm on a business trip to Jinghai,
正好我去京海出差
so I thought I'd drop by.
顺便过来看看
How's the shipyard negotiation going?
造船厂谈得怎么样了
Just the two of you?
怎么就你俩
Where are Xiaoning and Yuhui?
小涂跟小唐呢
I didn't expect you
我没有想到纪总
to be so concerned
对于我们造船厂
about the loan
贷款的事情
for the shipyard.
这么上心呀
Regarding that project,
那个项目
Xiaoning has nearly wrapped it up.
小涂已经谈得差不多了
And we're all set
而且我们已经准备
to go back and start the process.
回去走流程了
Yuhui
小唐
went back early.
提前回去了
She's already checked in
今天已经到许力那儿
with Xu Li today.
报到过了
It seems
那看来
everything is going well.
效率挺高啊
Xiaoning and Yuhui
小涂跟小唐
did a great job this time.
这次做得也还不错
Mr. Ji,
纪总
did you just arrive today?
您是今天刚到吗
Yes.
对
I asked you this because yesterday
是因为昨天那个
Mr. Zhao mentioned he saw you.
赵经理好像说看见您了
You miss me that much?
这么想我
I must be drunken.
喝多了
I was seeing things; I also missed you.
看岔了也想你了
Let's go.
走吧
Time for breakfast.
吃早饭去
Well,
那
you two go ahead.
你们俩先去
I'll go back and get Xiaoning.
我回去叫一下小涂
This morning,
我这个早上
when I left the room,
出门的时候啊
I had no idea
我都不知道
if Xiaoning was in the room.
小涂在不在房间
Ji Yuheng, you animal!
纪昱恒这个禽兽
Xiaoning!
小涂啊
Xiaoning?
小涂
Ms. Rao.
姐
Still sleeping?
在呢
I'm here.
我在啊
What time is it?
几点了姐
Is it time to check out?
是不是该退房了
I overslept.
我起晚了
It's OK.
没事
If you're awake, why not get up?
醒了就起来
Get ready.
收拾一下吧
Mr. Ji is here.
纪总过来了
He mentioned
说是
he stopped by on his way back.
回城顺道过来看看
He's going back with us today.
今天跟我们一起回星城
Since you're awake,
那既然醒了
get up and get ready.
起来收拾一下吧
Let's have breakfast together.
一起吃个早餐
OK.
好
I'll wait for you at the breakfast spot.
吃早餐地方等你
Make it fast.
快点啊
Would you like some, Xiaoning?
要吗筱柠
No thanks.
不吃 姐
Alright.
好
Could you skip the beer?
能不能不喝啤酒了
When I
我现在
see someone drinking beer,
看见人喝啤酒
and when I smell it,
闻到这个味儿
I'll just...
我就
Don't throw up in here!
你别在这儿吐
It's so disgusting.
多恶心
I'll go get some water.
我去买几瓶水
I'll go with you.
我跟你去
Don't go, you!
你不能走
Hey,
我
Take your hand away.
你手先拿开
Before,
我以前
I never got seasick.
从来都不会晕船的
It must be the aftereffects
肯定是那天跟你喝那酒
from drinking with you that day.
留下的后遗症
You have to take care of me.
你得照顾我啊
Take care of you?
我照顾你
Why should I?
凭什么
Because
凭
you're in my debt.
我是你的债主
Fine,
好
I'll take care of you then.
我照顾你啊
Here.
来
Let me
给你
cool you down with this.
扇扇
Feeling better?
舒服吗
A bit better.
好一些了
Better, huh?
那你就好好享受啊
After all, it's going to cost you 2000
毕竟呢是两千块钱
for an hour.
一小时的服务
Why do I have to pay for this?
怎么还得要钱呢
You want it free? Fine.
不要钱也行
Give me clients from state-owned enterprises.
送我几个国企客户
Please at least act like a human being.
你还是人吗
I'm quite a lovely human being.
我这人做得挺好的
Give it to him, now.
赶紧给他
Take it, here.
你赶紧拿着来
You take one too.
姐 你一个
I'll give Mr. Ji one.
我去给纪总送一瓶
Alright.
行 那你给他送一瓶吧
Drink up!
喝呀
Hurry.
快点啊
Have some water.
喝水
Thanks.
谢谢啊
You don't look so well.
怎么看你脸色不好啊
Are you having a fever?
发烧了
No.
没
I'm just feeling really seasick today.
今天格外地晕船
What?
怎么
Aren't you worried they'll see us?
不怕他们看到啊
You're my superior.
你是我领导
It's
那
perfectly normal to take care of
领导身体不舒服
a superior who's unwell.
照顾一下也很正常
I think it's because
我觉得是不是因为
I was so exhausted last night.
我昨天累得
You have the nerve to bring that up.
你还好意思说
I covered it up with a lot of makeup.
我化了好多粉底遮住的
You should go back.
快回去吧
Drink up, OK?
喝水啊
Is Mr. Ji alright?
纪总没事吧
He's a bit seasick.
他有点晕船
You never get seasick?
你从来不晕船吗
I was seasick a little today.
我今天有点晕船
517, that's my taxi.
五一七
Ms. Rao.
姐
Mr. Zhao.
小赵哥
My taxi is here. I'm going first.
我车来了 我先走了
Mr. Ji, see you.
纪总我先走了
Have a safe trip home.
那你自己慢点啊
Let me help you with that.
我帮你拿吧
Thanks, Mr. Zhao.
谢谢小赵哥
No problem.
没事
Get in.
走
Get in the car.
你先上车坐着
Come on.
你上车
See you, Ms. Rao.
走了静姐
See ya.
小心点啊
Later, Xiaoning.
走了小涂
Later.
拜拜
Hello?
喂
Sorry,
不好意思啊
I'm quite far from you.
我这儿离你有点远
I won't make it.
过不去了
Please call another one.
你重新叫一下吧
How could you just cancel on me?
你怎么能说取消就取消
Let me tell you,
我跟你讲
I'll file a complaint against you.
你这样我可以投诉你的
Hello!
喂
Ms. Rao,
饶经理
my ride is here.
我车到了
If you want, I can give you a ride,
要不我不计前嫌
putting aside our past grievances.
捎你一段吧
Mr. Ji, where's your ride?
那纪总你车呢
Mine
正好
should be here any moment now.
我的车马上就到了
You two go ahead.
你们先走吧
OK, see you then.
好 那我们先走了
I'll get that.
箱子给我吧
Get some rest.
回去好好休息啊
Hello?
喂
They've left.
他们走了
Okie Dokie.
好嘞
Coming.
来了
What are you smiling about?
偷笑什么呢
I just find it quite amusing.
就觉得还挺有意思的
Are you feeling any better?
你好点了吗
Yes.
好点了
What's up?
怎么了
It's Mr. Zhao.
小赵哥
Get down, now!
快下来 下来 下来
Young folks these days.
世风日下呀
Get up.
起来吧
Why does it feel like
怎么觉得
after the trip,
出去一趟
there're no safe places
回来
on this planet?
哪儿哪儿都危险
It's even more dangerous than before.
比以前更危险了
If Mr. Zhao and Ms. Rao
小赵哥和静姐
found out about
知道咱们俩
us dating,
谈恋爱了
then it wouldn’t take long
那不出半天
for everyone to find out.
肯定人尽皆知
Yeah,
你别说
it's actually quite thrilling.
还真挺刺激
But it could also be
不过也可能
because we're
会不会是因为我们
getting too intimate.
太过于亲密了
That's perfectly normal.
那也很正常呀
We are
咱们俩
about to get married.
都快要结婚的人
It's only natural
亲密一点
to be intimate, right?
不是很正常吗
You're absolutely right.
说得对
We're getting married soon.
快结婚了
I said 12; he's running late again.
说好的十二点 又迟到
I'm Qi Yu.
我叫齐郁
Hello, sir.
叔叔好
Hello, sir. I'm Qi Yu.
叔叔好 我叫齐郁
I went to the same college
是跟惟依之前
with Weiyi.
是大学同学
We are
我们两个是
in a romantic relationship.
男女朋友关系
Don't be so uptight.
你别紧张
My dad isn't scary.
我爸又不是老虎
He won't bite you.
不会把你吃了的
Um,
那个
did you mention to him
你跟叔叔说
what my current job is?
我现在的工作了吗
I did tell him.
说了
Would he consider my job...
他会不会觉得这份工作
It's fine.
没事
I don't even care about it.
我都不在意
What does he care?
他在意什么
It's not like he's the one dating you.
又不是他跟你处对象
Sweet heart.
小宝
He's here.
来了
Dad.
爸
You may leave us.
你们先去忙吧
You've been waiting for a while, right?
等着急了吧
You must be famished.
是不是饿坏了
Why didn't you reply to my messages?
你怎么都不回我消息啊
I was in a meeting.
爸爸开会呢
Hello, sir. I'm Qi Yu.
叔叔好我叫齐郁
Here's a little gift.
这些是我的一点心意
You're being kind.
你客气了
You really didn't have to do this.
其实不用带这些的
I have a last-minute
我一会儿临时
meeting to attend soon.
有个事情要谈
Let's not eat elsewhere.
我们就不到外面去吃了
Let's have dim sum in the conference room.
到会议室 吃点简餐
Dad.
爸
I gave you a heads-up
我提前那么久
well in advance.
跟你打过招呼
Why is there suddenly a meeting?
怎么突然要开会啊
That's not fair.
不行
I want to eat somewhere else.
我就要出去吃
It's fine.
没事
His work is important.
叔叔工作要紧吗
Eating in the conference room is fine.
在会议室吃简餐也挺好
It's convenient.
方便
Alright then.
行
Let's go.
过来吧
How can we eat in the conference room?
怎么能在会议室吃呢
It's all the same.
在哪儿吃不一样
Come on, don't be upset.
走 别生气
Dad!
爸
Have some of this.
多吃点
Yu,
小齐啊
what do you do for a living.
现在在哪儿高就呢
Dad.
爸
Didn't I mention it to you before?
我不是跟你说过了吗
My daughter,
我这个女儿啊
I've really spoiled her rotten.
真的都让我给惯坏了
Please be more patient.
你平时一定要多担待啊
Not at all.
没有 没有
Weiyi is truly wonderful.
惟依特别好
She's a fantastic girl.
人好
Her personality is great too.
性格也好
Great personality?
性格好
Yeah.
也是
Lovers find beauty beyond the surface.
情人眼里出西施
You young folks,
你们现在年轻人
when it comes to relationships,
谈恋爱啊
you always get impulsive.
就是容易上头
Dad.
爸
Is my personality really that bad?
我平时性格难道不好吗
Good, good.
好 好 好
When in love,
谈恋爱呢
it's natural to be impulsive.
需要瞬间上头
But to maintain a lasting relationship,
不过想要长久维系
you need to be rational.
那得靠理性
As for me,
我呢
I'm not an old-fashioned person.
也不是什么迂腐的人
I don't care about the house you live in
什么家住哪里呀
or how much
条件怎么样啊
money you have.
我都不是很在乎
But there's one thing I value highly,
不过有一点我很看重
and that is
那就是
a man
一个男人
must have ambition.
一定要有上进心
Only then can the two of you
这样两个人的日子
build a good life together.
才能过起来吗
Sir, don't worry.
叔叔您放心
I'm preparing to take the police exam.
我已经在准备考警察了
Where are you at now?
你现在到哪一步了
Have you passed the written test?
笔试过了吗
Dad!
爸
This exam
这个考试
is held every year
它每年都有
at a fixed time.
固定的时间的
You don't know anything about it,
您什么都不懂
so maybe it's best to leave him be.
就别问了吧
Sir, don't worry.
叔叔您放心
I'm already preparing for it.
我已经在准备了
I'll do my utmost
我会尽我所有的努力
to pass it.
争取通过
Please trust me.
相信我
How about this?
那这样吧
Let's put your relationship
你跟依依的事情呢
with Weiyi on hold for now.
先放一放
Let's wait after you pass it,
等你考过了以后再说
alright?
好吧
Dad!
爸
Let's eat.
吃饭
Slow down.
走慢点
Why did you
你刚刚为什么要
stop me earlier?
拦着我呀
Why should we put it on hold?
什么叫先放一放
Who can predict the result of the exam?
那考试的事谁说得准吗
His expectations of me
叔叔对我提的要求
aren't unreasonable.
也不过分
He's not asking me to be filthy rich.
他没要求我家财万贯
He just wants me to have ambition
只要求我有上进心
and to be dependable.
能说到做到
He cares about you,
他是因为爱你
which is why he has expectations of me.
才对我提出要求的
But just like he said,
但就如他所说
that exam is really tough.
那公检法那么难考
What if...
那万一
I'm not the sharpest tool in the shed.
我承认我脑子笨
But hard work can make up for that, right?
但勤能补拙不是吗
I've signed up for a tutoring class.
我报了补习班
I've been sticking to
也一直按照
the study plan I created.
列的计划在复习
I can't guarantee
我没有办法跟你
a 100% success,
做百分之百的承诺
but I will definitely
但我一定会
give it my all.
尽自己最大的努力
Just trust me.
相信我
Alright then.
行吧
I'll help you prepare for it.
那我陪你一起
Maybe you could
说不定你还真
pass on your first try.
一次过了呢
You live in such a high-end neighborhood.
你说你住这么贵的小区
No wonder you can't save any money.
难怪攒不住钱
You always go for the best in everything.
衣食住行你都挑最好的
You really
你真是
don't hold back on yourself.
一点不亏待自己啊
What's wrong?
你怎么了
You look so pale.
脸色这么难看
I'm fine.
没事
My stomach is acting up.
胃病犯了
Having some hot water should help.
喝点热水就好了
Let me help you upstairs.
那我扶你上去吧
Hands
手
off.
拿下去
By the way, my place
我跟你讲我们家
is not open to strangers.
不招待外人
And another thing,
还有
don't think that just
别以为在我老家
because you met my parents
见了我父母
and shared a couple of drinks with me
跟我喝了两顿酒
that we have a close bond.
咱俩就有交情了
When it comes to competing for clients,
后边抢客户的时候
I won't go easy on you.
我也绝对不会手软
Thanks.
谢谢
See ya.
再见
That's not what I meant.
我是这个意思吗
Li Xiang,
李想哥
come over here!
快过来呀
Even though I didn't buy much,
虽然买得不多
please, all of you, help yourself.
大家尝个新鲜呗
Thanks.
谢谢 谢谢
Thank you, Xiaoning.
太谢谢小涂
No problem.
不客气
Mr. Zhao,
赵哥
Xiaoning bought us gifts over there.
小涂给我们带了土特产
Ms. Rao brought us souvenirs.
静姐给我们拿了纪念品
What about you?
你呢
I just went on a business trip
我就只是去
and didn't make any money.
去出了个差又没赚钱
It wasn't a vacation.
又不是去旅游
Let's skip gifts.
干吗带礼物啊
How stingy!
抠门
Besides,
再说
Ms. Rao brought you souvenirs
饶经理送礼物
because Xihai Town is her...
是因为西海镇是她的
My what?
西海镇是我什么
It's your town of fortune.
西海镇是你的福地
Your apprentice signed contracts.
带出的徒弟签了客户
That's your blessing.
是你的福气
Exactly.
是的
Here, Mr. Zhao.
小赵哥
Thanks.
谢谢
Where's Yuhui?
小唐呢
She's not feeling down after
她不会是没竞争过小涂
losing to Xiaoning, is she?
受打击了吧
No,
没有
she applied for a new business trip.
她签了新的出差申请
She won't be back before the New Year.
年前应该不会再来了
Another business trip?
又出差
This girl is really resilient.
这小姑娘是越挫越勇啊
It's so lively here!
这么热闹
Gifts?
特产啊
Is there any for me?
有我的吗
Boss,
领导
you're getting funnier!
越来越幽默了啊
Didn't you go to
你自己不都去了
Xihai Town yourself?
西海镇吗
You also went to Xihai Town?
领导也去西海镇了
To cheer for your juniors?
给师妹加油去了
What are you talking about?
说什么呢
Li Xiang.
李想
Xiaoning.
小涂
You...
你
hurt your neck?
脖子受伤了
It's OK.
不是
It was the boat.
那个船啊
It was rocking badly.
太晃了
I lost my balance
我没站稳
and
就 就
and got scratched by a wire.
被那个铁丝给刮了一下
How careless.
怎么这么不小心
Just recently,
正好
I cut my hand
我前段时间裁纸的时候
while trimming paper.
手被划伤了
I still have some meds here.
这儿还有药呢
Hey,
这样
let me get you the meds.
我把药拿给你
You should let Ms. Rao help you apply it.
你让你师父帮你涂一点
It's OK.
不用 不用
It's just a minor scratch.
就一点小伤
Really, it's not necessary.
真的不用
Listen,
我跟你说
pay attention to small injuries.
这种小伤特别要注意
That's fine.
不 不
Especially scratches from metal items,
尤其是金属划伤的
they can easily leave scars.
很容易留疤的
Honestly, it's really not necessary.
真的不用 真的不用
Guys,
各位
I have some
有一个好消息
good news to share.
跟大家说一下
This month, Ms. Rao
饶经理这个月
has brought in three new clients.
新增了三家民企客户
As expected from our
不愧是咱们
star employee in section one.
拓展一部的业务担当啊
I'll keep pushing forward, everyone.
我再接再厉 各位
Did I hear that right?
我没听错吧
Three clients?
三个
Ms. Rao,
饶经理
you're awesome!
厉害呀
Seems you're the type who pretends to
看来你就是那种
have fun with classmates during the day
白天假装跟同学玩儿
and studies hard
晚上回家
at night.
发奋学习那种人
Do I have to pretend with you?
跟你玩儿还用假装吗
Help Xiaoning
把这个药给小涂
with this.
涂上
Stomach pain again?
又胃疼
If you're injured, cut down on coffee.
受伤了少喝咖啡
It can lead to pigmentation.
容易色素沉淀
Have some red dates water.
喝点红枣水
It's just a minor scratch.
小赵哥我就一点小伤
You really don't need to fuss over me.
没事不用这么照顾我
We're
咱们
all comrades in the same boat.
都是一个战壕的战友
It's natural to look out for one another.
相互照顾是应该的吗
I've still got one left here.
我这儿还剩了一杯
It's not taken.
没人喝
How about this,
这样
take it to Ms. Rao.
给你师父送过去吧
Thanks, Mr. Zhao.
谢谢小赵哥
No problem.
不客气
Ms. Rao,
静姐
this is from Mr. Zhao.
小赵哥给的
What's this?
这什么
Red dates water.
红枣水
How come Mr. Liu
这个老刘
has so many packages?
怎么这么多快递
Let me see.
我看看
Your skin looks so radiant today.
你今天这个皮肤嫩得
Seems you could squeeze water out of it!
可以掐出水来呀
Love really is
果然爱情就是
the best beauty treatment.
最好的医美
What?
干吗
After a few days
过了几天
in a whirlwind of passion,
干柴烈火的日子
and now you're treating me as an outsider?
把我当外人了呗
I knew it!
我就知道
This Ji Yuheng,
这个纪昱恒啊
- he definitely... - Shut up!
肯定 闭嘴
What's wrong with you?
你怎么回事
Can you please
以后能不能
stay at least 1km away
离开这个大门
from this gate
一公里以外
before you mention Ji Yuheng's name?
再说纪昱恒的名字
I just landed a client,
我这刚找到客户
and I really don't want to get fired.
我可不想被开除了
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
我错了 我错了
I just wanted to express my thoughts.
我就是想表达一下吗
A guy like this,
你说这种
who is both talented and good-looking,
又有实力 又有颜值
and willing to be with you every day.
还能天天陪着你
How did such a great guy
这种好男人
suddenly
是怎么突然就
popped up
从天而降
out of nowhere,
嘭的一下
and jumped right into your arms?
扑到你怀里去的呀
Luck is also a kind of strength.
运气也是实力的一种
What's wrong?
怎么了
Is Mr. Qi
齐先生
not perfect enough?
不好了不够完美了
You don't like him anymore?
不喜欢了
Of course he's great.
他当然很好喽
But you have no idea
但你是不知道
how hard he's been working lately.
他最近有多拼命
His persistence...
那执拗劲
drives me nuts.
都快把我逼疯了
What happened?
怎么了
Just think about it,
你说说看
he's worked so hard,
他都已经这么努力了
and if he still doesn't pass the exam...
这万一最后还是没考过
wouldn't that be...
那 那岂不是
Unjust.
天理难容
Exactly.
对呀
He's really done so much
他为了跟你在一起
to be with you.
真的做得已经够多了
When does he take the exam?
他什么时候考试
Today.
今天
No wonder
怪不得
you seem so distracted today.
你今天魂不守舍地
Don't worry.
不要担心了
How about this,
要不这样
I'll share some of my good luck
我把我考试
from passing my exam with him.
通过的运气分他点
No, you can't do that.
这使不得
You are at a critical stage to get permanent contract
你转正的事迫在眉睫
and you can't afford to lose any luck,
这运气不能分出去
not even for Qi Yu.
哪怕是齐郁也不行
It's fine.
没事
It seems a sure thing now,
我现在转正都靠谱了
so I'll share some with Mr. Qi
分给齐先生一点
and wish him
祝他
good luck with his exam.
顺利通过考试
You're a true friend,
还是姐妹好
really loyal.
够义气
I'm off, Xiaoning.
走了小涂
Bye.
拜拜
-Bye. -Bye.
拜拜 拜拜
Xiaoning,
小涂
aren't you off work yet?
下班了还不走啊
You go ahead, Fanggang.
小赵哥 你先走吧
I have a
我还有个
financial report to review.
财务报表要审一下
Life is long.
人这一辈子长着呢
Don't push yourself all the time.
不要时时刻刻都拿命拼
When it's time to clock out, clock out.
该下班下班
When it's time to live, live.
该生活生活
Otherwise,
否则
money's in the bank, you're in heaven.
钱在银行 人在天堂
What's the point?
有什么用啊
Learn from your mentor;
学学你师父
she works hard during the day,
上班的时候拼命
but once it's off work,
下班的时候
who knows where she's off to enjoy life.
不知道跑哪儿潇洒去了
I'm out.
走了
Bye.
拜拜
I'm off, boss.
走了领导
All right.
好
Finally, everyone's gone.
终于都走了
Uh...
那个
Still here this late?
这么晚了还没下班啊
I was just about to head home.
我正准备回家呢
What's wrong? Didn't you already leave?
你怎么了 不是走了吗
I forgot my badge.
我这工牌拿掉了
I'm heading out now,
我先走了啊
bye.
拜拜
Mr. Zhang,
张哥
I'm on my way.
我在过来的路上呢
Coming.
来了 来了
Wait for me.
等我啊
So...
那个
Since you're heading out,
既然下班要走
shall we go together?
要不一起吧
Sure, Mr. Ji.
好呀 纪总
Let's go.
走吧
Mr. Ji.
纪总
Xiaoning,
小涂啊
how's
最近
work going lately?
工作还顺利吗
It's going well.
挺顺利的
Thank you, Mr. Ji.
谢谢纪总
Come here.
来
What's up?
干吗
No one else is around.
没人
Qi Yu?
齐郁
I had planned to take the day off
那个 我今天本来
for my exam and wasn't
是请假去考试
at the company,
没去公司
but since the manager is leaving
然后行长明天要出差
on a business trip tomorrow,
我就提前把车
I went back to the office
都收了一下
to
就
sort things out early.
临时回了趟公司
I messed up.
我错了
I swear,
我发誓
I didn't mean
我绝对不是
to tell him
有意把你俩的事
about you two.
告诉他的
Blame it on the enemy
你要怪就怪
being both simple and cunning,
敌人单纯又狡诈
which lowered my guard.
降低了我的防备心
Just one question,
我 问一句啊
Qi Yu wouldn't
齐郁应该不至于
rat us out, right?
出卖我们吧
No, no, no,
不会 不会 不会
he wouldn't.
他肯定不会
If he ever dares,
他要是敢出卖你们
I'd be the first to take him down.
我第一个宰了他
Promise.
表态
I won't.
不会 不会
All right,
好了
today,
今天呢
to show my apologies,
为表我的歉意
I'm covering
今晚所有的消费
all the expenses tonight.
本小姐买单
Excuse me,
服务员
two bottles of Blue Ribbon.
要两瓶蓝带
We don't usually drink like this.
我们平时不这样喝的
Your apology comes
你这道歉的成本
with a hefty price tag.
有点高啊
Let's have fun.
开心吗
Today's a good day.
今天是个好日子
First,
一呢
I'm apologizing
我是为
for telling Qi Yu
把你们的事告诉齐郁
about you two,
我道歉
and second,
这二来呢 跟我们道歉
we're celebrating
就是为了正式庆祝一下
you two...
你们俩
we're celebrating Qi Yu
正式地去庆祝一下
successfully finishing his exam.
齐郁成功考完试
I did pretty well
我那个笔试
on the written exam;
考得确实还行
I think I've got
我觉得
a good chance of passing.
很有希望通过
Really?
真的假的
That's great!
太好了
Come on, cheers!
来 来 来
Congratulations!
恭喜 恭喜
So,
怎么样 怎么样
keep going?
还玩吗
Of course.
怎么不玩
Come on,
走
let's go dance.
跳舞去
Didn't you say you wouldn't dance?
不是不跳舞吗
So...
你说
Sit down.
坐
Our girlfriends
我们女朋友
are best friends,
是好朋友
so we should be
那咱们也算是
good friends too, right?
好朋友呗
Calling you Mr. Ji feels too formal.
我再叫你纪总有点生疏
If I call you by your full name,
我叫你全名
it feels weird.
奇怪
Yuheng?
昱恒
Feels a bit too intimate.
有点暧昧啊
You can call me whatever you want.
想叫什么都可以
I'll just call you Yuheng.
我就叫你老纪
Yuheng.
老纪
Sure.
可以
Come on,
来
Yuheng,
来老纪
let's drink.
喝一个啊
Are you going to the bathroom?
你去不去上厕所
What?
什么
Hey,
姐姐
are you alone?
一个人吗
No,
不是
I have a boyfriend.
我有男朋友
A boyfriend?
有男朋友
You're not making that up
该不会是为了
to turn me down, are you?
拒绝我编出来的吧
My boyfriend
我男朋友
is really handsome.
真帅
Listen,
听好了啊
I won't interfere
我是不会干涉
with your hobbies.
你的爱好的
But next time if you're going out,
但是下次如果再来
make sure to tell me in advance.
一定要记得提前告诉我
If you
要不然
get drunk,
你喝多了
I won't be able to be there right away.
我没办法第一时间就在
What,
怎么
you want me to report to you?
你要让我跟你报备啊
Not satisfied?
还不满意啊
Well, that depends on your behavior.
那我要看你表现
I'm not kidding,
我真没和你吹
bro,
哥
I can handle a whole bottle.
我一斤酒真没啥事
And even if I do get drunk,
而且我喝多了
I don't transform or anything.
我也不变身啊
So you're saying
你这意思是
I transform when I'm drunk?
我喝多了变身啊
Go ask around,
你出去打听打听
I've been
我赵方刚
a client manager for years
当客户经理这么多年
and never embarrassed myself
什么时候因为
because of drinking.
喝醉酒丢过脸
It's recorded now.
录下来了啊
Recorded.
录下来了
Go ahead, record it.
录呗 你录呗
I did.
我录了啊
You're bragging.
你这吹牛
Let's be real,
要说啊
the worst drinker
论酒品
in our entire office
咱们整个办公室
is...
最差的是
Even if my drinking is bad,
我酒品再不行
I've never thrown up in someone's car
我也不吐人家车上
and not paid for the car wash.
洗车钱都不给人家
We're not that bad, right?
咱没差成那样啊
Did I do
我昨天
anything weird yesterday?
没做什么奇怪的事吧
Seems like drinking
看来喝酒这件事
isn't for me.
真不适合我
Does falling asleep curled up
刷牙时蜷在洗手台上
on the bathroom sink while brushing
睡着了
your teeth count?
算吗
But it was pretty cute.
但是挺可爱的
Red... Red envelope!
红 红包
Boss,
领导
you're really generous today.
大手笔呀
You're giving away
你这是
your fortune.
散尽家财
Everyone,
各位
it's almost New Year's.
还有几天就要过年了
We've successfully met
咱们顺利完成了
the bank's deposit target.
行里给的存款任务
These small red envelopes
小红包呢
are just to bring some good luck.
给大家讨个彩头
The year-end bonus
年终奖
will be settled after the holiday.
节后就给大家结算
Great!
好啊
Yeah!
好
-Thank you, Mr. Ji! -Thank you, Mr. Ji!
谢谢纪总 谢谢纪总
Not bad, Mr. Ji,
可以啊纪总
learning how to win people over.
学会收买人心了
Xiaoning, you're flattering me.
小涂谬赞
This money came from an extra bonus,
这笔钱用的额外的奖金
not from
不动用
our shared savings.
我们共同的小金库
Are you all going back home?
你们过年都回老家吗
I'm not going back this year.
我今年就不回去了
I've planned a trip
我约了哥几个呢
with some friends.
出去旅游去
What about you guys?
你们呢
I'll spend it with my family.
我 我跟家里人过
Boss,
领导
what about you?
那你呢
Me too,
我也是
with some very important family members.
跟很重要的家人一起
Fanggang,
小赵哥
what about you?
你呢
I'm not so lucky.
我就没那么好的命了
My whole family's going to
我这一大家子
my brother's place for New Year's,
都去我弟弟那儿过年了
so I'll be all alone.
孤家寡人
You're probably spending it alone too.
你应该也是一个人吧
How about
要不
we pair up for New Year's?
咱俩凑个过年搭子
Even at my worst,
我再不济
I don't need to pair up with you.
也不用跟你搭一起
Didn't mean it,
不愿意算了
just joking around.
本来就是开玩笑的
Ha.
搞笑
Xu Li,
许力
revise it again.
再修改一下吧
You're just taking it out on me.
你这是公报私仇
Go revise it.
修改去吧你
Come on.
来
Mr. Ji, you've got good taste.
纪先生眼光不错呀
This guesthouse is really nice.
这个民宿很好
Today is our first New Year's together
今天是咱们一家人
as a family,
第一次一起过年
so we should be comfortable.
肯定得住得舒服点
This place is spacious.
这里宽敞
It's got two floors.
这儿有两层楼呢
You've thought of everything.
你想得真周到
Otherwise, with the five of us,
要不然我们五口人
there'd be no room
不管是住咱们那儿
whether we stayed at our place
还是住我妈那儿
or my mom's.
都住不开
We wouldn't be able to stay up together.
就没有办法一起守岁了
Exactly.
是
Let's go.
走
This way?
往这边走吧
Yes.
对
Are you sure you don't need
你一会儿确定
my help later?
不用我帮忙
If you help, we might
你帮忙我怕
end up eating New Year's dinner
这顿年夜饭啊
next year.
得吃到明年了
Dad, Mom.
爸 妈
Where is everyone?
怎么没人呀
Dad,
爸
Mom?
妈
Are they not here?
没在吗
I'll go check.
我去看看
Okay.
好
Everything's still here.
这东西都在呢
No one's here.
没有人
Maybe give them a call?
要不打个电话吧
Phone's ringing.
电话来了
Hello, Dad,
喂 爸
where are you?
你们在哪儿呢
Uh...
那个
do you have a moment?
你现在有没有空啊
Can you come pick us up?
过来接一下我们
Just don't tell Xiaoning, okay?
你千万别跟筱柠说啊
Why can't you tell me?
为什么不能跟我说
What happened?
怎么了
N... nothing,
没 没事
we're fine.
我们好得很
Just a
就是发生了一点
little mishap.
小小的意外
Hello?
喂
What happened?
怎么了呀
What kind of mishap?
什么小意外
Where are you?
你们在哪儿啊
What were you doing?
你们干什么去了
Catching a chicken.
抓鸡呀
I can see it's a chicken,
我知道这是鸡
but whose idea was this?
谁出的主意啊
It was mine.
我呀
Wait,
这
why are you catching a chicken?
大过年的你抓什么鸡啊
You could've just bought one
你去菜场买一个
at the market.
不就行了
You can't get it at the market.
菜场哪能买到这种鸡啊
This is a free-range chicken,
这叫走地鸡
and it's tastier.
这儿的鸡好吃
So
所以呢
we came here
我们就上这儿来
to catch one.
抓一只鸡
We have everything for New Year's,
家里年货啥都有
just needed the chicken.
就缺鸡了
Dad, Mom,
爸 妈
it's cold in the mountains.
这山里也冷
Let's get in the car first.
先上车再说吧
Yes, hurry.
那赶紧 赶紧 赶紧
Bring it over.
赶紧拿来
Come on.
来 来 来
Quick, quick.
快 快 快
-Put it in the car. -Mom.
放车上 妈
Let's get in the car first.
先上车吧
Your hands are dirty, Dad.
你这手脏的呀 爸
Just sit tight.
好好待着吧
Here,
快
wipe your hands.
把手擦擦
Get in the car.
快上车吧
Sure.
好
Dad,
爸
tell me honestly,
你说实话
was this Mom's idea?
是不是我妈的主意
It was mine.
我
my idea.
我的主意
Would you dare go catch a chicken
我妈要不同意
if Mom didn't agree?
你敢去抓鸡
This yard is really nice,
这院子真不错
isn't it?
是不是
Yes,
是啊
I wonder who picked it.
不知道他们谁挑的
I think I didn't buy any chicken.
我好像是没买鸡
That's not good.
那不行吧
We need chicken,
这过年
duck, fish, and meat for New Year's.
鸡鸭鱼肉都得全啊
Yeah.
对啊
Are you serious?
不是你真的假的
Seriously.
真的
How about
那要不
I call Yuheng to come back
我打电话让小恒回来
and drive us to that...
开车带咱们去那个
They say there's a farmers' market.
说是有农贸市场
We can go buy it there.
咱们去买吧
It's going to take a long time
这一来一回的
to go back and forth.
多长时间哪
I just remembered,
我想起来了
on the way here,
咱们来的那个路上
I think there was a farmhouse
好像有个农家乐
that sells free-range chickens.
有卖走地鸡的
How about we go catch one there?
要不然咱们去抓吧
It's New Year's.
这大过年的 你说
Just drop it.
快拉倒吧
It's not worth it
这为了一只鸡
for a chicken.
这犯不上的
It's because you
就是因为你
didn't prepare all the New Year's goods,
没有把年货备齐
now we don't have chicken
现在害的咱们大过年的
for the New Year.
没有鸡吃
This is a chance to make up for it,
给你一个弥补的机会
and you're not taking it?
你还不珍惜
Are you going or not?
你去不去
Next time my mom
下次我妈
comes up with such a bad idea,
再出这种馊主意
try to stop her.
你拦着点
My mother-in-law
我婆婆那
is still sick.
不是生着病呢吗
If something happens,
万一出点什么事
we're far from the hospital
荒郊野岭的
in this remote place.
离医院这么远
It's really inconvenient.
多不方便
Right, right,
对 对 对
I didn't think of that.
我没想到这点
That's my oversight.
那是我考虑不周
It won't happen again.
下不为例啊
Celebrating New Year, what's the point?
没事过什么年呀
It's so boring.
多无聊啊
Who is it?
谁啊
I haven't even ordered my takeout yet.
这外卖还没点呢
Happy New Year.
新春快乐
Can I come in?
我能进去吗
Come in.
进吧
Take off your shoes.
脱鞋
Can you
麻烦
put them in the shoe cabinet for me?
你帮我放鞋柜啊
Your house is really big.
你家也是够大的啊
If I remember correctly,
我没记错吧
today's New Year's Eve, right?
今天是大年三十啊
Is there a problem?
有问题吗
I brought some New Year's goods!
我准备了年货
You startled me.
一惊一乍的
I'll put them over there.
我给你放那儿去
Sure.
好啊
Your lipstick color is really nice.
今儿口红颜色挺好看的
It's New Year's after all.
过年吗
Come on,
来 来 来
everything's ready.
这都贴好了
We need to take a photo.
我们得拍张照
What's there to take a picture of?
这有什么可拍的
Quick, quick.
快 快 快
Three, two, one,
三 二 一
Happy New Year!
新年快乐
This one's too thick.
太厚了你这个
Don't make the center so thick.
你这中间别这么厚
Look.
给你看
Are you making pancakes?
吃烙饼啊
Look at this.
我本来啊
I was worried that Jing
还害怕静姐
would be lonely
一个人过春节
spending the New Year alone,
怕她会孤独呢 你看
but look at what Fanggang did.
小赵哥弄的
Isn't the atmosphere perfect?
是不是氛围感满满
It really is nice.
还真是不错
Quite romantic too.
还挺浪漫的呢
Here,
来
taste this for seasoning.
替我尝尝咸淡
Delicious.
好喝
It's good?
还可以
It smells so good.
好香 好香
I've been sitting here,
我刚坐在这儿
smelling it the whole time.
一直闻到香味
What's the filling?
这什么馅的呀
It's your mother-in-law's
这是你婆婆
secret
独家祖传的
three-delicacy filling.
秘制三鲜馅
What secret?
什么秘制啊
It's just
就是
spinach,
菠菜
shrimp,
虾仁
and pork,
猪肉
then
然后呢
it's quickly sautéed
再用料油
with some flavored oil.
给它激一下
Try it later
等会儿吃
and see if you like it.
看好不好吃啊
Are you making dumplings?
你要包饺子啊
Let me help.
帮忙啊
Come on,
你快拉倒吧
you'll end up
你这两下你回头
with dumplings
捏不紧
that fall apart in the pot.
成一锅片汤了
Dad, you always complain
爸你看看你啊
that I don't know how to do anything,
一边嫌弃我什么都不会
but then you never let me try.
一边又什么都不让我做
That's not fair!
你这不是欺负人吗
Just let me try it.
我试试吗
What if I have
万一我是有
a hidden talent for this?
这方面天分呢
Look at her, look at her.
你看 你看 你看
This kid.
这孩子
Come on,
你快拉倒吧啊
your happiness is spilling over.
你这幸福都溢出来了呀
Don't waste it.
糟蹋东西
It's fine.
挺好 挺好
By the way,
对了啊
I'm putting
我这个
a coin in this one.
包硬币的
Look,
你看
whoever gets
包个硬币
the dumpling
谁要是吃到
with the coin
这个带硬币的呢
will have
今年啊
good luck this year.
一定会顺顺利利地
Then I'll put in a red date.
那我就包个红枣吧
Here.
来
Mom,
妈
the coin
这
brings good luck,
硬币是顺顺利利
but what does the red date mean?
红枣是什么呀
You don't know?
你不知道啊
I don't know.
不知道
Yuheng.
小纪
Yes?
妈
Do you know what
你知道饺子里
putting a red date in a dumpling means?
包红枣什么意思吗
Of course I know, Mom.
当然知道了 妈
What does it mean?
啥意思
You don't know?
你不知道
Tell her.
你跟她说说
I don't know.
我不知道
It means "to have a baby soon."
早生贵子
Xiaoning is sure
我们筱柠肯定能
to get that dumpling.
吃到这个饺子啊
It's New Year's.
这大过年的
If I suggest fireworks,
一起放个烟花
she probably won't refuse, right?
她应该不会拒绝吧
But
但是
we don't know each other that well...
我们俩好像也不太熟啊
How should I ask?
怎么跟她说呀
I'm just getting some fresh air.
我出来透透气
Ji Yuheng?
纪昱恒
It really is you!
真是你呀
What are you doing here?
你怎么在这儿
Relatives in this neighborhood?
你有亲戚住这个小区吗
I just bought
我刚好在附近
some fireworks nearby...
买了些烟花
Xiaoning,
筱柠
do you want to
要不要
come down and set off fireworks?
下楼放鞭炮了
What did you say?
你说什么
I said, do you want to...
我说要不要
Put on your coat
快穿衣裳
and come down.
下来 下来
Got it.
知道了
Happy New Year.
新年快乐